in this video we're going to look at the
在这个视频中，我们将看
equilibria of infinitely repeated games
无限重复博弈的均衡
so in order to talk about equilibrium we
所以为了谈论平衡，我们
need to begin by asking what are we
首先要问我们是什么
going to mean by a pure strategy in an
将意味着一个纯粹的战略
infinitely repeated game and you may
无限重复的游戏，您可能
like at this point to pause the video
喜欢在此时暂停视频
and see if you can answer that question
看看你能否回答这个问题
before I go on and tell you the answer
在我继续告诉你答案之前
if you need a hint you should remember
如果您需要提示，请记住
that the rule of thumb that we've used
我们使用的经验法则
to define strategies as we've changed
定义我们已经改变的策略
game representations has been to say
游戏表示一直在说
that a pure strategy should be whatever
一个纯粹的策略应该是什么
you would need to tell another person to
您需要告诉其他人
play in the game on your behalf and to
代表您参加游戏，并
end up doing exactly what you would have
最终完全按照自己的意愿去做
done so a pure strategy has always kind
做到这一点，纯策略总是善良的
of been the policy that you would you
一直是你要的政策
would follow making all of the decisions
将遵循所有的决定
in the same way as you would have
以与您原本相同的方式
actually done it so whatever you would
实际上做到了，所以随便你怎么
need to communicate about that policy
需要就该政策进行沟通
well in an infinitely repeated game your
在无限重复的游戏中
strategy is going to be a choice of
策略将是
action at every decision point that you
在您做出的每个决策点采取行动
would have which means an action that
会有一个动作
you would take at every stage game and
您会在每个阶段的游戏中
bear in mind that when you take those
请记住，当您服用那些
actions you actually get to reason about
您实际上要推理的动作
everything that you've seen before in
您之前所见过的一切
the game which is to say you can
这个游戏可以说你可以
remember all of your own previous
记住你以前所有的
actions and you can also remember all of
动作，您还可以记住所有
the actions in previous stage games by
前阶段游戏中的动作
the other players so so really your pure
其他玩家真的很纯真
strategy space is a mapping from every
战略空间是每个方面的映射
history to an action choice that you
您选择动作的历史
would make clearly this is an infinite
会清楚地表明这是无限的
number of actions so unlike the previous
动作数量，因此与之前不同
games we've looked at extensive form
我们看过的游戏形式广泛
games and normal form games you're not
游戏和非正规游戏
even going to have a finite set of pure
甚至会有一组有限的纯
strategies in an infinitely repeated
无限重复的策略
game let me give you some examples of
游戏让我给你一些例子
some famous pure strategies in
一些著名的纯策略
infinitely repeated games nevertheless
无限重复的游戏
to give you the sense that we can say
给您一种我们可以说的感觉
interesting things about pure strategies
关于纯策略的有趣的事情
even though the set of possible pure
即使这组可能的纯
strategies is infinite so think about
策略是无限的，请考虑
playing repeated prisoner's dilemma so
反复犯人的困境
I'm gonna play the prisoner's dilemma
我要扮演囚徒的困境
game infinitely one famous strategy is
游戏无限一项著名的策略是
called tit-for-tat turns out that there
所谓的针锋相对
were
是
famous competitions where people
人们著名的比赛
submitted programs that played a
提交播放过
prisoner's dilemma very repeatedly and
囚犯的困境非常反复，
then they looked at how these programs
然后他们看了这些程序
did against each other and tit for tat
互相对抗，针锋相对
was a strategy that famously did really
这是著名的策略
well in those competitions the way it
在那些比赛中
works is it starts out cooperating and
可以开始合作了
then if it observes that its opponent
那么如果它观察到它的对手
defect everett effects or in the
埃弗里特缺陷效应或
previous round the opponent defected
上一轮对手叛逃
then tit for tat defects in the next
然后在接下来的针刺中剔除针刺缺陷
round then it goes back to cooperation
一轮，然后回到合作
so then if it defected but its opponent
所以如果它叛逃但它的对手
cooperated then it'll respond to that by
合作，然后它将通过
cooperating
合作
so if tit for tat plays itself it'll
因此，如果针锋相对发挥自己的作用，
cooperate forever but if it plays
永远合作，但是如果合作
against somebody who defects it's going
反对那些有缺陷的人
to intuitively kind of punish that
直观地惩罚
defection by defecting itself in the
通过背叛自己而叛逃
next round but it's very forgiving it's
下回合，但这是非常原谅的
going to go back to cooperation after
以后要回去合作
one punishment
一种惩罚
in contrast the trigger strategy is kind
相反，触发策略是一种
of a really mean-spirited version of tit
一个非常卑鄙的山雀版本
for tat so it starts out by cooperating
为达，所以它开始于合作
but if its opponent ever defects that's
但是，如果对手有缺陷，那就是
it it's just gonna defect forever so
它只会永远存在缺陷，所以
it's gonna pull a trigger and say I'm
它会扣动扳机，说我
never gonna forgive you you've wronged
永远不会原谅你你冤屈了
me once I'm gonna wronged you back until
我一旦我会委屈你，直到
the end of time that's why we call it
时间的终结，这就是为什么我们称其为
trigger so you can see that in both of
触发，因此您可以在两个
these cases I've been able to describe
这些情况我已经能够描述
to you how these strategies would
给你这些策略会如何
respond to anything from the infinite
回应无限的一切
history that they would see kind of in
他们会看到的历史
algorithmic terms without actually kind
没有实际种类的算法术语
of writing out a strategy kind of in a
在某种程度上写出一种策略
formal language so you can see that it
正式语言，以便您可以看到
is possible to think kind of coherently
有可能连贯地思考
about interesting strategies and
关于有趣的策略和
infinitely repeated games now of course
现在无限重复的游戏
what we would really like to do as game
我们真正想做的游戏
theorists is describe the Nash
理论家描述纳什
equilibria of infinitely repeated games
无限重复博弈的均衡
the kind of approach that we've taken in
我们采取的那种方法
the past has been to first of all show
过去一直到所有节目
how we can make an induced normal form
我们如何制作归纳范式
out of a game we figure out what a
从游戏中我们找出什么
strategy is in the game we show how to
策略是我们在游戏中展示的
make the induced normal form and then we
做归纳法线形式，然后我们
just appeal to Nash's theorem and say
只是呼吁纳什定理并说
because we've got a normal form game we
因为我们有一个普通的形式游戏
know that there is a Nash equilibrium
知道存在纳什均衡
and so everything kind of goes through
所以一切都会经历
the way it did before well that worked
之前效果很好的方式
well for us in the
对我们来说
because we always ended up with finite
因为我们总是以有限的结果
size to induce normal forms
大小以诱导正常形式
unfortunately because we have an
不幸的是，因为我们有一个
infinite number of pure strategies we're
无限数量的纯策略
gonna get an infinity by infinity matrix
通过无穷大矩阵得到无穷大
even in the two-player case and so we're
即使在两人游戏的情况下，所以我们
not gonna have something to which Nash's
不会有纳什的东西
theorem applies anymore
定理不再适用
because now we have an infinite sized
因为现在我们有一个无限的大小
game and Nash's theorem only works for
游戏和纳什定理仅适用于
finite games which means games whose
有限游戏
matrices are finite I contain to find
包含的矩阵是有限的
that number of numbers and that means we
该数量的数字，这意味着我们
we don't have any reason based on what
我们没有任何理由
we know so far even to be sure that
到目前为止，我们甚至可以确定
equilibria do exist in these games
这些游戏中确实存在均衡
on the other hand because there are an
另一方面，因为有一个
infinite number of strategies there
那里有无限数量的策略
might even be an infinite number of pure
甚至可能是无数个纯净的
strategy equilibria so we've seen the
策略平衡，所以我们已经看到了
fact that in the past it's possible to
过去有可能
have an infinite number of mixed
有无限数量的混合
strategy equilibria for example if I in
策略均衡，例如，如果我在
a normal form game have two strategies
普通形式的游戏有两种策略
two pure strategies that I've been
我去过的两个纯策略
different between than any mixture
不同于任何混合物
between them can also be a best response
他们之间也可能是最好的回应
for me so that there's a sense in which
对我来说，在某种意义上
I can have an infinite number of mixed
我可以有无数的混合
strategy equilibria but here I can have
策略平衡，但在这里我可以
an infinite number of qualitatively
定性地无数
different pure strategy equilibria
不同的纯策略均衡
potentially that seems like a problem so
可能这似乎是一个问题，所以
we're not going to be able to somehow
我们将无法以某种方式
list off the equilibria necessarily of a
列出必然的平衡
repeated game interestingly there is
有趣的是重复游戏
still something that we can coherently
仍然是我们可以连贯的东西
do to give a satisfying answer about the
给出一个令人满意的答案
Nash equilibria of infinitely repeated
无限重复的纳什均衡
games and in this video I'm going to
游戏，在这个视频中，我将
tell you what it is and actually because
告诉你这是什么，实际上是因为
it's so satisfying I'm even going to
真的很满足，我什至会去
prove this theorem to you so you'll
向您证明该定理，以便您
really will understand how this one
真的会了解这一个
works and here's the idea of the theorem
起作用，这是定理的想法
that we will eventually prove we can
我们将最终证明我们可以
characterize what payoffs can be
表征可能的收益
achieved under equilibrium and we can
在平衡下实现，我们可以
give an example of equilibrium
给出一个平衡的例子
strategies that result in those payoffs
那些带来回报的策略
without giving every equilibrium that
没有给出所有的平衡
results in those paths so we're going to
导致这些路径，所以我们要
kind of characterize which strategies
表征哪些策略
are in equilibrium in infinitely
无限地处于平衡状态
repeated games sort of via their payoffs
重复的游戏，例如通过回报
I'm going to be able to tell you
我会告诉你的
precisely which payoff vectors are
确切地讲，哪些收益向量是
achievable in equilibrium so to do that
达到平衡是可以做到的
I need to give you a little bit of
我需要给你一点
notation so we
符号，所以我们
talk about these payoff vectors so this
谈论这些收益向量
is kind of our slide of notation once we
一旦我们完成，这就是我们的符号幻灯片
get through this we're gonna have all
通过这个我们将拥有所有
the building blocks we need to prove out
我们需要证明的基础
there so we're going to start with some
在那里，我们将从一些开始
and player game so this is just our
和玩家游戏，所以这只是我们的
stage game some normal form game and
舞台游戏一些普通形式的游戏
we're also going to start with some
我们也将从一些
payoff vector here and by this what I
回报向量在这里，由此我
mean is the utilities that the players
意思是玩家的效用
get in the game now in this video I'm
我现在在这个视频中加入游戏
gonna talk about the average reward case
要谈论平均奖励情况
where each of these numbers actually
这些数字实际上在哪里
encodes the utility that I get on
编码我得到的实用程序
average by following my strategy in the
通过遵循我在
infinitely repeated game and so that's
无限重复的游戏，所以
gonna say I care just in the same way
会说我以同样的方式在乎
about payoffs that I get now and payoffs
关于我现在得到的收益和收益
that I get a million iterations into the
我得到了一百万次迭代
future
未来
we can do something similar in the
我们可以在
discounted reward case and that's gonna
打折的奖励案例，那将会
be the topic of a different video but
是另一部影片的主题，但
for this video we're gonna talk only
对于这个视频，我们只会说
about the average reward case and the
关于平均奖励情况和
reason is the proof is a little bit
原因是证明有点
easier to think about in the average
平均而言更容易考虑
reward case even though the discounted
奖励案例，即使打折
reward reward case is maybe a bit more
奖励奖励案例可能更多
of a practical setting we can get across
我们可以了解的实际环境
the the key ideas of both proofs by this
这两个证明的关键思想
proof and this one's a bit easier so so
证明，这有点容易，所以
let's do it to do that I need to remind
让我们做到这一点，我需要提醒
you of the concept of the min Max value
最小最大值的概念
here which is something that we kind of
这是我们有点
introduced in the concept of zero-sum
零和概念引入
games but it turns out to be very
游戏，但事实证明它非常
important for repeated games so I'm
对于重复游戏很重要，所以我
going to remind you of what it is here
会让你想起这里的一切
so this is the mathematical definition
所以这是数学上的定义
of the mid max value but let me start by
最大值的中间值，但让我开始
saying in words what it means because
用语言说这是什么意思，因为
the the nested min and Max operators are
嵌套的min和Max运算符是
a little bit hard to think about
有点难以思考
essentially with what eyes min Max value
本质上用最小的眼睛看最大值
is is it's the amount of utility that
是它的实用性
player I is able to obtain for himself
我可以自己获得的玩家
if all of the other players who we call
如果我们打电话给其他所有玩家
- I are completely unconcerned about
-我完全不关心
their own utility and instead they're
他们自己的实用程序，而是
just trying to hurt I as much as
只是想尽可能地伤害我
possible so they all play that strategy
有可能，所以他们都扮演这个策略
from their joint mixed strategy space
从他们联合的混合策略空间
that if I respond to that by doing the
如果我通过做出回应
best thing that I can for himself
我能为自己做的最好的事情
then eyes utility is as low as possible
那么眼睛的实用性越低
so they're trying to minimize eyes
所以他们正在努力减少眼睛
utility given that I is trying to
鉴于我正在尝试实用
maximize in response to their
最大限度地回应他们
minimization and the number that comes
最小化和随之而来的数量
out at the end is the amount of utility
最后是效用的数量
that I can get by doing as best he can
我可以尽他所能
against everybody trying to hurt him as
反对每个试图伤害他的人
much as possible
尽可能多
so that's eyes min max value so
所以眼睛最小最大值
intuitively if I want to punish you as
如果我想惩罚你
much as possible in a game and you know
在游戏中尽可能多地知道
that I'm trying to punish you that's the
我想惩罚你的就是
amount of utility that you get is your
您获得的实用程序数量是您的
min Max value so I will say that a
最小值最大值，所以我会说
payoff profile remember a payoff profile
支付配置文件记住支付配置文件
is a payoff amount for everybody is
是每个人的回报金额是
enforceable or give it the name
可执行的或为其命名
enforceable if it's the case that
在这种情况下可以执行
everybody's payoff and that payoff
每个人的回报，那回报
profile is at least their min Max value
个人资料至少是其最小值，最大值
so if anybody is getting less than their
所以如果有人比他们少
min Max value in a given payoff profile
最小给定收益曲线中的最大值
I will say that that's an unenforceable
我会说那是无法执行的
payoff profile and I will say that a
还清个人资料，我会说
payoff profile is feasible you I'll use
我将使用支付配置文件是可行的
this technical term feasible if the
如果该技术术语可行
following condition is true
以下条件为真
intuitively what I want to say about
直觉上我想说些什么
feasibility is that it's possible to
可行性是有可能
actually get that payoff profile by
实际通过
combining together payoffs in the actual
结合实际收益
game that's being played
正在玩的游戏
notice that enforceability doesn't
请注意，可执行性并不
actually require that it's possible you
实际要求有可能
know I could say the payoff 1 million
知道我可以说回报一百万
dollars for me a million for you in
一百万美元给我
prisoner's dilemma is an enforceable
囚徒困境是可以执行的
payoff profile because it's above both
支付配置文件，因为它高于两者
of our min Max values but there's no way
我们的最小最大数值，但是没有办法
we can actually each get a million in
我们每个人实际上可以得到一百万
prisoner's dilemma because the numbers
囚徒困境，因为数字
don't go that high so feasibility is
不要走得那么高，所以可行性是
going to talk about what it's actually
要说说它到底是什么
possible to do and the way we're going
可能做的事情以及我们要走的路
to say this is I'm going to restrict
说这是我要限制
myself to rational numbers I'm going to
我要去有理数
say if there exists rational and
说是否存在理性和
non-negative values alpha a such that
非负值alpha a这样
for all players I can express player i's
对于所有玩家，我可以表示玩家我是
element from this payoff vector as a sum
此收益向量中的元素作为总和
over all of the payoff profile
在所有的支付配置文件中
action profiles in the normal form game
正常形式游戏中的动作配置文件
of this alpha a x eyes utility for that
该alpha斧眼实用程序的
a so intuitively oh and then of course I
这么直观哦，然后我当然
need this let me just say this last part
需要这个让我只说最后一部分
of the condition that these alphas all
这些alpha都满足的条件
sum to one across all of the action
在所有动作中求和
profiles so let me kind of explain to
个人资料，让我来解释一下
you what this means so so I have kind of
你这意味着什么，所以我有点
a normal form game and what I want to
普通形式的游戏以及我想要的
say is I have some weight on each cell
说我每个单元格都有重量
in the game these are the Alpha A's and
在游戏中，这些是Alpha A和
they all sum to one and what I want to
它们全部合为一，而我想要
do is take my payoff from this cell
要做的就是从这个单元中获得收益
weighted by the alpha for that cell my
由该单元格的alpha加权
payoff for this next cell weighted by my
下一个单元的收益由我加权
alpha for that cell and sum all of those
该单元格的Alpha值并将所有这些值相加
those weighted utilities for me up and
那些加权的公用事业对我来说
then I get alright so I what I want to
然后我就好了，所以我想要
say is there exists alpha s that I could
说有存在我可以的alpha s
use that would blend together the
使用将融合在一起
payoffs in the actual game in such a way
以这种方式在实际游戏中获得收益
that I get RI and furthermore that has
我得到了RI，而且还有
to simultaneously be true for everybody
同时对每个人都真实
else and in particular it has to be true
否则，尤其是它必须是真实的
with the same alpha as for everybody
与每个人的alpha相同
else so I can come up with some alphas
否则我可以提出一些Alpha
that make that get me my RI but then I
这使我得到了我的注册商标，但后来我
have to use those same alphas to get RJ
必须使用相同的Alpha来获得RJ
for player J I have to have the same
JI玩家必须有相同的
weights on all of the DES cells here so
这里所有DES电池的权重
that I get the same numbers for
我得到相同的数字
everybody so so let's think about the
大家都这样，让我们​​考虑一下
following game which will give you an
以下游戏将为您提供
example of how feasibility works so
可行性如何运作的示例
let's say I have a game that looks like
假设我有一个看起来像
this
这个
so in this game I claim the payoff
所以在这个游戏中我要求回报
profile 1/1 is enforceable and the
配置文件1/1是可执行的，
reason is I can put a weight of 50% on
原因是我可以将50％的重量放在
this cell a weight of 50 percent on this
这个电池的重量为50％
cell and weights of zero on these cells
像元，这些像元的权重为零
and you can see my payoff in this game
你可以在这个游戏中看到我的收益
is 50% times 2 plus 0 times 0 plus 0
是50％乘以2加0乘以0加0
times 0 plus 50% times 0 which is 1 the
0乘以50％乘以0，即1
other players payoff in this game is 50%
此游戏中其他玩家的收益是50％
times 0 plus 0 times 0 plus 0 times 0
0加0乘0加0乘0
plus 50% times 2 which is also 1 so that
加50％乘以2也等于1，这样
is a feasible payoff in this game on the
是这个游戏中可行的回报
other hand the payoff to 2 is not
另一方面，对2的回报不是
feasible in this game and the reason is
在这个游戏中可行，原因是
there's no way that I can have weights
我不可能有重量
on these cells that sum up to 1
在这些单元格上总计为1
and that give both of us to because for
这给了我们俩，因为
me to get a payoff of 2 this would have
我得到2的回报
to be 1 that's the only cell where I get
成为1，这是我得到的唯一单元格
a payoff at all and for my opponent to
完全是对我的对手的回报
get to this one would have to be 1 and
达到这一点必须是1并且
then they would both sum up to more than
那么它们两者的总和将超过
than 1 this condition over here would be
比1这个条件在这里是
violated and so we just can't do it so
违反了，所以我们做不到
that's not a feasible path ok now we're
那不是可行的路线，现在我们
ready to prove the folk theorem so and
准备证明民间定理
it's kind of funny it's called the folk
这很有趣，被称为民间
theorem it's kind of like a folk song
定理有点像民歌
for mathematicians so a folk song is a
对于数学家来说，一首民歌是一首
song that everybody knows but nobody
大家都知道但是没人的歌
really knows who wrote it first and a
真的知道是谁先写的
folk theorem is a theorem that people
民间定理是人们的一个定理
all kind of knew and talked about before
以前都知道和谈论过
they got around to writing it down and
他们到处写下来，
they're not really sure quite where it
他们不太确定到底在哪里
came from so this is the folk theorem of
来自，所以这是
game theory and despite having uncertain
博弈论，尽管不确定
origins it's it's very important so in
起源很重要，所以在
the folk theorem basically tells us what
民间定理基本上告诉我们什么
the Nash equilibria are of an infinitely
纳什均衡是无限的
repeated game in terms of these payoffs
在这些收益方面反复进行游戏
and in terms of
而就
definitions that I just told you so
我刚才告诉你的定义
there are different folk theorems for
有不同的民间定理
different settings this is the folk
不同的设置，这是民间的
theorem for infinitely repeated games
无限重复博弈定理
with average rewards so the folk theorem
具有平均回报，所以民间定理
has two parts which basically stems from
基本上有两个部分
the fact that I've made a restriction
我已经限制的事实
here to rational alphas turns out we
在这里有理性的阿尔法证明了我们
don't actually need that but the math
实际上并不需要，但数学
gets more annoying if we have to deal
如果我们必须处理，会变得更烦人
with real values so to keep things
具有真正的价值，以便保留事物
simple I'm doing this just for rational
简单，我这样做只是为了理性
numbers so the folk theorem says that in
数字，所以民间定理说
any end player game which we're going to
我们要进行的任何最终玩家游戏
repeat infinitely and for any payoff
无限重复并获得任何回报
vector r1 to RN just like we've been
就像我们以前一样，将向量r1传递给RN
talking about well first of all we're
首先谈论好我们
gonna talk about the case where if R is
要说说如果R是
the payoff in a Nash equilibrium of the
纳什均衡的收益
infinitely repeated game with average
无限次重复平均游戏
rewards what we can conclude about the
奖励我们可以得出的结论
payoff vector and what we conclude is
收益向量，我们得出的结论是
that for every player R has to be
对于每个玩家R必须
enforceable remember enforceable means
可执行记住可执行的手段
greater than or equal to that players
大于或等于该玩家
mid max value so I can conclude that if
中间最大值，所以我可以得出结论，如果
R is the payoff in an equilibrium of the
R是在
infinitely repeated game with average
无限次重复平均游戏
rewards then for everybody that R must
然后为R必须给的每个人奖励
be enforceable that seems like kind of a
具有可执行性，似乎有点像
weak thing to say the second part of the
薄弱的事情要说第二部分
folk theorem is kind of more surprising
民间定理有点让人惊讶
it says basically that's the only
它说基本上这是唯一的
restriction we need if R is enforceable
如果R是可执行的，我们需要的限制
and furthermore if it's feasible if it's
而且如果可行的话
kind of possible to make it out of the
一种可能使它脱离
payoffs of the game then R is the payoff
游戏的收益，那么R是收益
in some Nash equilibrium so together
在纳什均衡中
what this says is that basically
这基本上是说
feasibility and enforceability is the
可行性和可执行性是
whole story of Nash equilibrium and
纳什均衡和
force ability seems like this very small
力量似乎很小
thing it says you're getting no less
它说你越来越少的事情
than the payoff that you get if everyone
比每个人都能得到的回报
punishes you as much as it's possible
尽可能地惩罚你
for them to punish you and feasibility
让他们惩罚你和可行性
says it's kind of possible to get these
说有可能得到这些
payoffs in the game at all and the folk
游戏中的回报以及所有
theorem says that's basically it as long
定理说基本上就是这样
as you meet those two conditions you've
当您满足这两个条件时
got a Nash equilibrium that's
纳什均衡是
basically what there is to say about
基本上有什么要说的
Nash equilibrium you'll notice this
纳什均衡，你会注意到这一点
there's a little bit of wiggle room
有一些摆动的房间
between these two statements two parts
这两个语句之间分为两个部分
of the theorem statement which has to do
定理陈述的说明
with the fact that we're talking about
我们正在谈论的事实
feasibility here and we're not talking
这里的可行性，我们不是在谈论
about it here so we can't conclude that
关于它，所以我们不能得出结论
every Nash equilibrium is feasible you
每个纳什均衡都是可行的
might wonder why that is that's just
可能想知道为什么那只是
because some of them aren't expressible
因为其中一些无法表达
as rationals some of them they alphas
作为理性，他们中的一些人
wouldn't be rational so so that's the
不会是理性的，所以这是
part that I'm kind of leaving out of
我有点忽略的部分
this proof but that that's a technical
这个证明，但这是技术上的
point so the broad thing that you should
指出如此广泛的事情
remember about the folk theorem is that
记得关于民间定理是
basically feasibility and enforceability
基本的可行性和可执行性
together are equivalent to Nash
一起相当于纳什
equilibrium in repeated games so if if
在重复游戏中保持平衡，如果
you wanted to stop here you now know
你想在这里停下来，你现在知道
what the folk theorem is but I encourage
民间定理是什么，但我鼓励
you to keep watching the rest of the
你继续看剩下的
video and you'll see how we actually
视频，您会看到我们实际上如何
prove this there so let's begin by
在那里证明这一点，让我们开始
saying proving the first part so saying
说证明第一部分
why is it that if the payoff is
为什么会得到回报
achievable in a Nash equilibrium that I
在纳什均衡中可以实现的
can conclude that it must be enforceable
可以得出结论，它必须是可执行的
well to prove this I'm going to prove by
很好地证明这一点，我将通过
contradiction so I'm going to begin by
矛盾，所以我将开始
supposing that the payoff vector is not
假设收益向量不是
enforceable and if not that means that
可执行的，如果不是，则意味着
there must be some player I for whom his
我一定有某位球员
payoff RI is strictly less than his mid
回报RI严格小于他的中位数
max value now let me consider a
现在让我考虑一个最大值
situation in which this player I changes
我改变这个球员的情况
his strategy let's imagine that he
他的策略让我们想象他
instead deviates to playing bi of s
而是偏向于玩s的bi
minus IH I'll tell you in a second what
减去IH，我稍后再告诉您
that means any time he's in a history H
这意味着他有任何历史H
of the repeated game so what is this
重复游戏的结果，这是什么
thing it says this is the strategy of
它说这是策略
the other players let's assume that he
其他球员让我们假设他
gets to know what that is because we're
知道那是什么，因为我们
talking about a Nash equilibrium and and
谈论纳什均衡，以及
we'll say bi is just his best response
我们会说bi只是他最好的回应
every time the other players are playing
每次其他玩家在玩
their strategy profile s - I give an H
他们的策略简介-我给H
for every history H so let's just
对于每一个历史H
consider a case where he just best
考虑一个他最好的情况
responds to what the other players are
对其他玩家的反应
doing well by the definition of a mini
迷你的定义做得很好
Mac strategy you have to get a payoff of
Mac策略，您必须获得回报
Atlee
阿特利
german max value in every stage game if
每个阶段游戏中的德国最大价值
you follow this strategy that we just
您遵循这一策略，我们只是
defined because remember the definition
定义是因为记住定义
of a min max value is that you get is
最大值的最小值是
that everyone is trying to hurt you as
每个人都试图伤害你
much as possible and that your best
尽可能地做到最好
responding to that so intuitively if I'm
如果我很直觉地回应
already getting less than my min Max
已经低于我的最小最大
value that means I can't be best
意味着我不能做到最好
responding to everybody else because if
回应其他人，因为
they're trying to hurt me as much as
他们正尽力伤害我
possible which is the worst case for me
可能这对我来说是最坏的情况
and I'm best responding to them I will
我最好回应他们，我会
get my min Max value so intuitively I
如此直观地获得我的最小最大值
could change my strategy to best
可以将我的策略改变为最佳
responding and that has to improve
回应，这有待改善
things for me that would have to bring
给我带来的东西
me up to my mid max value and because
我达到我的中间最大值，因为
that would improve my utility that's a
那会改善我的效用
better response for me than what I was
对我而言，反应比以前更好
doing before and because so basically
之前做过，因为基本上
here we've just kind of constructed a
在这里，我们只是构建了一个
profitable deviation for player I and
玩家I和
because a profitable deviation exists
因为存在有利可图的偏差
for him that means the strategy he was
对他来说，这意味着他的策略
playing before couldn't possibly have
玩之前不可能
been in Nash equilibrium and so that
处于纳什均衡状态，因此
leads us to to derive a contradiction
导致我们产生矛盾
from our assumption that we made at the
根据我们在
beginning that our was not enforceable
开始我们无法执行
so you can see we can conclude that if R
所以您可以看到我们可以得出结论，如果R
is not enforceable we we can't have a
无法执行，我们无法
Nash equilibrium and and that that been
纳什均衡，那是
proved what we wanted to prove that
证明了我们想要证明的
being in a Nash equilibrium implies
处于纳什均衡意味着
enforceability so that's part one that's
可执行性，这是
kind of the easy direction and the less
容易的方向和更少的方向
interesting direction let's now do the
有趣的方向，让我们现在做
the second and more interesting part
第二个更有趣的部分
which says all I need to assume is that
这说明我需要假设的是
the payoff profile is both feasible and
收益概况既可行又可行
enforceable and that means that I have
可执行的，这意味着我有
found a Nash equilibrium and what's
发现了纳什均衡，什么是
interesting about this part is that
这部分有趣的是
we're going to do it by construction so
我们将通过施工来做到这一点
I'm going to show you how if you're
我要告诉你如何
given any feasible and enforceable
给出任何可行且可执行的
payoff profile you can build a set of
您可以建立一套
strategies for both players which are in
双方球员的策略
equilibrium with respect to each other
彼此平衡
and which obtain exactly that average
并获得准确的平均值
payoff for both players so first of all
双方球员的回报，所以首先
let's just kind of introduce some
让我们来介绍一些
bookkeeping notation that we'll use here
我们将在此处使用的簿记符号
so
所以
since our is feasible and since we've
因为我们可行，而且
assumed that these alphas are rational
假设这些alpha是合理的
then we can write each RI as follows so
那么我们可以如下写每个RI
basically we can make up new variables
基本上我们可以组成新的变量
beta a and gamma where we replace each
beta a和gamma，我们分别替换
alpha a by beta a divided by gamma and
alpha a除以beta a除以gamma和
basically that's not hard to do because
基本上这并不难，因为
we know that the Alpha is irrational so
我们知道Alpha是不合理的
we know that we it's possible to write
我们知道我们可以写
each of these alphas as a fraction and
这些alpha分别作为分数和
then we can make gamma into their common
然后我们可以将伽玛变成它们的共同点
denominator and we can set the betas
分母，我们可以设置beta
appropriately and then it's possible to
适当地，然后有可能
come up with betas and gammas that make
提出了使
this expression true so so so that
这个表达如此真实，以至于
shouldn't be too surprising that just
应该不会太惊讶
follows from from the fact that these
从这些事实
alphas are rational and from feasibility
alpha是合理且可行的
now I'm going to construct a strategy
现在我要制定一个策略
profile and then on the next slide I'm
个人资料，然后在下一张幻灯片上
going to argue to you that that strategy
会跟你说那个策略
profile is in equilibrium or that we can
轮廓处于平衡状态，或者我们可以
turn it into an equilibrium so let's
把它变成平衡，让我们
make a strategy profile that cycles
制定一个循环的战略概况
through all of the outcomes using cycles
使用周期遍历所有结果
of length gamma and the way it's going
伽玛的长度及其发展方式
to work is that it's each cycle is going
工作是每个周期都在进行
to repeat action a exactly beta a times
重复执行一次完全beta的操作
so we're gonna have our kind of game
所以我们要有自己的游戏
matrix here and remember beta and gamma
在这里矩阵并记住beta和gamma
are both integers so so for example
都是整数，所以例如
let's say here we have let's say we have
让我们在这里说我们有让我们说我们有
gamma is 7 and let's say here we have
伽玛是7，我们在这里说
banished to so here alpha a is 2 over 7
被放逐到此处，因此alpha a是7分之2
let's say here 0 / 7 0 / 7 I'll just
让我们在这里说0/7 0/7
write the betas from this point on 0 1
从现在开始在0 1上写beta
to 0 to 0 so let's say that's that's
从0到0，所以说那是
what we had in this particular game then
然后我们在这个特定游戏中拥有的
what the strategy would do is that's
该策略将要做的是
just gonna cycle through so player 1
只会循环播放，所以玩家1
strategy would be to play let's give
策略就是玩，让我们给
these names a b c d e f so player 1
这些名称abcdef所以玩家1
strategy would be to play a a b
策略是打aab
be CeCe and then go back and keep doing
成为CeCe，然后回去继续做
that forever and player2 strategy would
永远和玩家2的策略会
be to play D d e f F EE and then go back
打D def F EE然后回去
and so if the two players played those
所以如果两个玩家玩过
two sets of strategies together in a
两组策略合在一起
coordinated way forever they would cycle
他们永远循环的协调方式
through exactly hitting every action
通过精确地击中每一个动作
profile in this game according to the
根据该游戏中的配置文件
betas in just the way that the betas say
Beta就像Beta所说的那样
and and let's denote such a sequence a
并且让我们表示这样一个序列
to the T now let me make strategy the
现在让我制定策略
the real strategies for the players that
玩家的真正策略是
I'm gonna claim or an equilibrium here
我要在这里求平衡
let's define a strategy si of player I
让我们定义玩家I的策略si
to be a trigger version of this strategy
成为该策略的触发版本
so if nobody deviates then si tells the
因此，如果没有人偏离，那么si会告诉
player to play just what 80 would tell
玩家玩80会告诉你的
them to play so the players are going to
他们玩，所以球员们要
begin by kind of cycling through these
通过这些骑自行车开始
outcomes in just the way that I told you
就像我告诉你的那样
but if one player notices that the other
但是如果一个玩家注意到另一个
player didn't do what they were supposed
玩家没有按预期做
to do according to 80 then they're gonna
根据80做，然后他们会
hit the trigger and instead from that
击中触发器，而不是从那
point on they're gonna play the min/max
点，他们将播放最小/最大
value against the other player so if it
对其他玩家有价值，如果
started that that's just what this says
开始就是这样
here so if there's ever a period in
因此，如果有一段时间
which somebody does the wrong thing then
那有人做错了什么
everybody's gonna gang up on that person
每个人都会帮那个人
forever and play the min/max play the
永远播放最小/最大播放
strategy against that person that causes
针对导致该人的策略
that person to get their min max value
该人获得他们的最小值最大值
so so let me just say that one more time
所以让我再说一遍
to make sure we've all got it so so 80
确保我们都做到了80
is a sequence where which is constructed
是构造的序列
so as to hit every action profile here
以便点击这里的每个动作档案
it's exactly the number of times given
就是给定的次数
by these beta integers and we disciple
通过这些beta整数，我们成为门徒
through that forever and the strategy
通过永远和策略
were interested in is a trigger version
感兴趣的是触发器版本
of that that says everyone tries to do
其中说每个人都想做
that but if somebody does the wrong
那但是如果有人做错了
thing
事情
everybody punishes them forever and
每个人都永远惩罚他们，
gives
给
max value okay so I want to claim that
最大值可以，所以我想声明
this is a Nash equilibrium of the
这是纳什均衡的
infinitely repeated game with average
无限次重复平均游戏
rewards so first notice that if everyone
奖励，所以首先要注意的是，如果每个人
does play according to this strategy
确实按照这个策略进行比赛
then everyone will get an average payoff
那么每个人都会得到平均回报
of RI just as we want it now you might
RI就像我们现在想要的那样
be thrown off by the fact that that
被以下事实抛弃
sometimes they're not quite getting RI
有时他们不太了解RI
because they're only midway through the
因为它们只是在
sequence but we're only interested in
顺序，但我们只对
the limit and so if you look at average
极限，所以如果你看平均值
is over a period of time of length gamma
超过了一段时间伽玛
so you look at what happens after gamma
所以你看看伽玛之后会发生什么
what happens after to gamma what happens
伽玛之后会发生什么
after three gamma
三伽玛之后
you'll you'll be able to convince
你会说服的
yourself that they really do get the
你自己，他们确实得到了
right payoffs because indeed after every
正确的回报，因为确实在每次
period of length gamma they get exactly
伽玛的长度，他们得到确切
the payoff all right by construction so
建造的收益还可以，所以
so indeed this does lead to the payoff
所以确实确实带来了回报
that we're trying to get what remains to
我们正在努力使剩下的东西
show is that this is a Nash equilibrium
证明这是纳什均衡
that nobody can gain by deviating and
没有人可以通过偏离获得
indeed I claim that it is so to show
确实，我声称它是如此显示
that let's let's imagine that everyone
让我们想象每个人
else is playing according to the
否则根据
strategy and some player J deviates at
策略，某些玩家J偏离了
some point well if that happens that for
如果发生这种情况很好
all time after that point player J is
在该点之后，玩家J一直
gonna get his mid max payoff and that's
会得到他最大的收益
gonna render the deviation unprofitable
会使偏差无利可图
because we've assumed that this payoff
因为我们认为这是回报
profile is feasible and enforceable and
简介是可行且可执行的
that means that he was already getting
那意味着他已经在
at least his mid max value and because
至少是他的中间最大值，因为
this is gonna happen for all time right
这将永远存在
this is gonna happen forever afterwards
这将永远发生
that's just gonna end up dominating the
那将最终主导
average everything that's happened for
平均发生的一切
that finite amount of time beforehand is
预先确定的时间是
gonna be washed out of the average and
会被洗掉
instead his average payoff is going to
相反，他的平均收益是
turn out to be his his minimax payoff
原来是他的极小收益
and by our but by the the thing we're
靠我们，但靠我们
trying to prove here we know that that's
试图证明这里，我们知道那是
less than or equal to RJ and so there's
小于或等于RJ，所以有
no reason that he can gain by such a
没有理由他可以通过这样的收获
deviation and that suffice is to prove
偏差，足以证明
the folk theorem so
民间定理
so what we've seen now is that
所以我们现在看到的是
essentially feasibility and
本质上是可行的
enforceability correspond to the payoff
可执行性对应于回报
profiles that are achievable in Nash
Nash中可实现的配置文件
equilibrium of an infinitely repeated
无限重复的平衡
game with average rewards
平均奖励的游戏